SUMMARY:

Experience in Analysis, Design, and Development of web applications with DotNet. Innovative approach to problem solving from engineering perspective. Team player, actively contributing to all stages of software development life cycle (SDLC), including requirements gathering and module integration. Analytical thinker, monitoring projects to ensure adherence to specifications and identifying areas of potential design enhancements.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Programming Languages	C++, Java, Python, Swift, Objective-C,
Web Technologies	HTML, CSS, Vue, JavaScript, Bootstrap
Database Systems	MySQL, MSSQL
Operating Systems	MacOS, Windows, Ubuntu
Development tools	Visual Studio, Xcode, Eclipse
Design Patterns	MVC, Singleton
Development Frameworks	asp.net, asp.net mvc, jsp, java servlet, CISCO packet tracer
Servers	Apache Tomcat, XAMPP
Version Control	Git, SVN
SDLC	Waterfall, Agile, Iterative, Scrum
Web Service	REST, SOAP

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern Sarvanam Software Pvt. Ltd.

Software Developer(Internship)

- Renovation of POS module of Hospitality management system
- Data collection and billing as per the user requirements
- Automated Report generation for different outputs.

Work Cygnus Tech Pvt. Ltd.

Junior Software Developer

Development of E-commerce websites

Kathmandu, Nepal Oct 2018-Jan 2019

sundaracharya096@gmail.com

Kathmandu, Nepal

Mar 2019 - Jan 2020

• Requirement analysis and modeling of system

PROJECTS

Smart Canteen (Web application)

- Designed fully functional Website application using HTML, CSS, Java Script, .net, MS SQL
- Created requirements document and design document for the functional and non- functional requirements.
- Purpose: Develop and Implement IOT in Canteen
- Objective: Implement system with Recommendation using collaborative filtering

Golden Fried Chicken (Web Application)

Designed fully functional web admin panel using HTML, CSS, Java Script, .net, MS SQL

Sarvanam Management Information System

- User validation via IP address detection
- Client data management
- Clients Software License generation and management
- File transfer system for new changes to the software

EDUCATION

CCNA Certification Course

Prime College

Prime_College affiliated to Tribhuvan University) Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology	Kathmandu, Nepal March 2019
Kathmandu Barsha College affiliated to HSEB Nepal Science	Kathmandu, Nepal 2014
Dhaulagiri English Boarding School School Level Certification	Baglung, Nepal 2012
Training / Certification MTA Networking Fundamentals Microsoft Innovation Center	February, 2016
Web Development IT Training Nepal	Jan 2017- April 2017
.Net Programming ITTN Nepal	Jan 2018- May 2017

Mar 2019- May 2019